A Guide to the Inge Horton Architectural Collection, 1964-1999
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Inge Horton Architectural Collection 1964-1999
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1990-065
8 boxes, 9.3 cu. ft.
Architect and architectural historian born in Germany. Planner with the Planning Department of the City and County of San Francisco, California, from 1983 to 1998; member of the Board of Advisors for the International Archive of Women in Architecture. Papers consist of architectural studies written while in Germany; presentations made at various women's architectural organization meetings, including the International Union of Women Architects; a curriculum vitae; and research files on early women architects in the San Francisco Bay Area.
Inge Horton
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Inge Horton Architectural Collection was donated to Special Collections in 1990 and 2013.
Biographical Information
Born in Germany. Horton was educated in architecture and city planning. She graduated with a Diplom-Ingenieur from the Technological University of Berlin, Germany, 1965, and with a Master of City and Regional Planning from University of California, Berkeley, 1979. She has work experience in private, institutional and municipal planning departments. She was a planner with the Planning Department of the City and County of San Francisco, California, from 1983 to 1998.
She has held leadership positions in both the Organization of Women Architects and Design Professionals (OWA) and the International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA). Her publications include several articles and two books in collaboration with Monica Hennig-Schefold on "Early Modern Architecture in Berlin" (1967) and "Structure and Decoration: Art Nouveau Architecture in Paris and Brussels" (1971).
Scope and Content
Papers consist of architectural studies written by Horton while in Germany; presentations made at various women's architectural organization meetings, including the International Union of Women Architects (UIFA); a Historic Structure Report for Julia Morgan building; copies of her books; a curriculum vitae; and research files on early women architects in the San Francisco Bay Area for her book "Early Women Architects of the San Francisco Bay Area: The Lives and Work of Fifty Professionals, 1890-1951" (2010).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged with respect to Inge Horton's original filing order.
Subjects:
History of Women in Architecture; International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA); Women architects--California; Women--History
Contents List
- Biographical information, curriculum vitae (Box-folder 1:1)
- Copies of presented papers,1981-1989 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Historic Structure Report for Julia Morgan's Petrero Hill neighborhood house, San Francisco, CA, prepared by Inge Horton, Horton Architectural Research, December 1999 (Box-folder 1:3)
- Fruhe Moderne in Berlin [Early Modern Architecture in Berlin], book, 1967 (Box-folder 1:4)
- Proposal for Citizen Review, San Francisco Department of City Planning, book, 1964 (Box-folder 1:5)
- Struktur und Dekoration,[Structure and Decoration: Art Nouveau Architecture in Paris and Brussels], book, 1967 (Box-folder 1:6)
- Werk, magazine, 1971 (Box-folder 1:7)
- Files of Early Women Architects and A Few Male Architects Who Supported Them, 1890-1951
  - Angell, Patricia Vaughn (1927- ), Patricia Vaughn Angell is a retired architect in Berkeley who graduated in 1960 with a B. Arch and 1961 with a M. Arch from UC Berkeley studying under Eric Mendelssohn and W.W. Wurster. She had no difficulties in fining positions in architect's offices and qualified for the state license in 1966. She started her own office out of her home and did not need to advertise her services. Together with her friend, Labelle Prussin, she researched the life and work of Julia Morgan shortly after Morgan's death in 1957 and having the article published in the Dictionary of American Biography, Supplement No. 6, 1956-1960. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Austin, Alice Constance, n.d. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Austin, Elizabeth May (1883-1968) (Box-folder 2:3, Box-folder 2:4)
  - Aycrigg, Helen E. Findlay (1894-1968) (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Baird, Mabel, n.d. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Bancroft, Ruth Peterson (1908-) (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Barden, Mary Margaret (1901-1989) (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Bassett, Helen Rearwin (1904-1996) (Box-folder 2:9, Box-folder 2:10)
  - Beck, Eunice Reed, n.d. (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Benbow, Helen (1898-1976) (Box-folder 2:12, Box-folder 2:13, Box-folder 2:14, Box-folder 2:15)
  - Benton, Ikna or Irene Inka Benton or Inka Sanna Benton, n.d. (Box-folder 2:16)
  - Bird, Grace Van Dyke (1892-1986) (Box-folder 2:17)
  - Born, Esther Francis Baum (1887-1902) (Box-folder 2:18, Box-folder 2:19, Box-folder 2:20)
  - Boutelle, Sara Holmes (1910-1999) (Box-folder 2:21)
  - Boyter, Elizabeth Mary (1896-1948) (Box-folder 2:22)
  - Bridgman, Lilian (1866-1948) (Box-folder 2:23, Box-folder 2:24, Box-folder 2:25)
  - Brown, Phoebe Hearst (1906-1990) (Box-folder 2:26)
  - Bruckman, Bettina, married name Cohen (1894-1986) (Box-folder 2:27)
  - Buckingham, Ada Dibble (1910-2004) (Box-folder 2:28)
  - Bussard, Elsa Mathilda Griesser (1900-1988) (Box-folder 2:29)
  - Carmel Women in Architecture, Builders and Contractors, n.d. (Box-folder 2:30)
  - Castelhun, Ella (1868-1961) (Box-folder 2:31)
  - Chadeayne, Olive Kingsley (1904-2001) (Box-folder 2:32, Box-folder 2:33)
  - Clever, Louise Harriet Ryssekk (1902-1980) (Box-folder 2:34)
  - Coblentz, Dorothy Wormser (1894-1988) (Box-folder 2:35)
  - Colter, Mary Jane (1869-1968) (Box-folder 2:36)
  - Connor, Rose (1892-1970) (Box-folder 2:37)
  - Deakin, Edna (1871-1946) (Box-folder 2:38, Box-folder 2:39)
  - Deirup, Anne Weymouth (1918-2003) (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Diment, Constance Shirley (1899-1972) (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Dodge, Ola Mae Putnam (1881-1964) (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Dows, Wena Waldner or Hughena Waldner Dows (1928-) (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Driskel, Jean Roth FAIA (1916-1971) (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Duddleson, Denise Leonard, n.d. (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Ehrenfels, Camille D'Evelyn Johnston (1878-1963) (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Eller, Armena Louise Morse (1896-1996) (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Emmons, Audrey Durland Ksanda (1921-1997) (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Fawcett, Marguerite Comfort (1900-1996) (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Fowler, Matilda "Tillie" Newsom (1868-1963) (Box-folder 3:11)
  - French, Helen Douglass (1901-1994) (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Frickie, Geraldine Russell Colby (1901-1963) (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Gannon, Mary N (1867-?) and Alice J. Hands, n.d. (Box-folder 3:14, Box-folder 3:15)
  - Gauen, Eileen Claudia Watkins (1920-2013) (Box-folder 3:16)
  - Gianturco, Valentine McGillycuddy (1906-1987) (Box-folder 3:17)
  - Gleason, Kate (Catherine Anselm) (1866-1933) (Box-folder 3:18)
  - Goodman, Michael Baltekal (1903-1991) (Box-folder 3:19)
  - Grant, Margaret (1901-1960) (Box-folder 3:20)
  - Gutterson, Henry Higby (1884-1964) (Box-folder 3:21)
  - Hall, Leola, married name Coggins, (1878-1930) (Box-folder 3:22, Box-folder 3:23)
  - Harris, Jessie, n.d. (Box-folder 3:24)
  - Harrison, Dorothy Gray (1909-1992) (Box-folder 3:25)
  - Hass, Myrtle Henrici (1894-1994) (Box-folder 3:26)
  - Hayden, Sophia Gregoria, married name Bennett (1868-1963) (Box-folder 3:27)
  - Hays, Elah Hale (1896-1986), Hays, Elah Hale (1896-1986) (Box-folder 3:28)
  - Hearst, Phoebe Apperson (1842-1919) (Box-folder 3:29)
  - Hook, Mary Rockwell (1877-1978) (Box-folder 3:30)
  - Howard, John Galen (1864-1931) (Box-folder 3:31)
  - Hufbauer, Arabelle "Trixie" Maxwell McKee (1914-2006) (Box-folder 3:32)
  - Jackson, Minnie M. (1883-?) (Box-folder 3:33)
  - Jewett, Grace (1876-1946) (Box-folder 3:34, Box-folder 3:35)
  - Jory, Grace Weeks (1889-1973) (Box-folder 3:36)
  - Karp, Eleanor Marilyn (1930-2006) (Box-folder 3:37)
  - Kartworld, Lois Beryl Goetz (1916-2006) (Box-folder 3:38)
  - Kavin, Eda (1914-2004) (Box-folder 3:39)
  - Keith, Alice Joy, n.d. (Box-folder 3:40)
  - Knapp, Charlotte Hastings (1894-1940) (Box-folder 3:41)
  - Kosmak, Evelyn Meta Hall Gilrest (1913-1983) (Box-folder 3:42)
  - Langhorst, Lois Wilson Worley (1914-1989) (Box-folder 3:43, Box-folder 3:44, Box-folder 3:45, Box-folder 3:46)
  - Lindheim, Roslyn Ittelson (1921-1987) (Box-folder 3:47, Box-folder 3:48)
  - Luis, Rosanna (Rose) Enos (1900-1993) (Box-folder 3:49)
  - Magee, Louisabelle Whyte (1911-1978) (Box-folder 3:50)
  - Majors, Cora C. (Box-folder 3:51)
  - Marriott, Bett Knisely (1914-2012) (Box-folder 3:52)
  - Martin, Lila Sweet (1860-1948) (Box-folder 3:53)
  - Martin, Mary Rebecca Kyle (1916-1997) (Box-folder 3:54)
  - Maybeck, Bernard Ralph (1962-1967) (Box-folder 3:55)
  - McAfee, Lucy Page Brown (1892-1923) (Box-folder 3:56)
  - McCain, Ida Florence (1884-?) (Box-folder 3:57, Box-folder 4:1, Box-folder 4:2, Box-folder 4:3, Box-folder 4:4, Box-folder 4:5, Box-folder 4:6)
  - Box 4 Index, n.d. (Box-folder 3:58)
  - Box 3 Index, n.d. (Box-folder 4:7)
  - McCoy, Esther (1904-1989) (Box-folder 4:8)
  - McKinnon, Mary Story Kilgore (1917-1993) (Box-folder 4:9)
  - McNaught, Polly Lawrence (1907-1982) (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Mead, Marcia (1879-1967) (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Mesic, Julian C. (initially known as Charlotte C. Mesick) (1889-1961) (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Meyers, Mildred Sophie (1898-1982) (Box-folder 4:13, Box-folder 4:14, Box-folder 4:15)
  - Morgan, Julia (1872-1967) (Box-folder 4:16, Box-folder 4:17, Box-folder 4:18, Box-folder 4:19, Box-folder 4:20, Box-folder 4:21, Box-folder 4:22, Box-folder 4:23, Box-folder 4:24, Box-folder 4:25, Box-folder 4:26, Box-folder 4:27, Box-folder 4:28, Box-folder 4:29, Box-folder 4:30, Box-folder 4:31, Box-folder 4:32, Box-folder 4:33, Box-folder 4:34, Box-folder 4:35, Box-folder 4:36, Box-folder 4:37, Box-folder 4:38, Box-folder 4:39)
  - Morin, Grace Evelyn (married name Van Blarcom) (1886-1974) (Box-folder 4:40)
  - Nevins, Kate (Kitty) Lockwood French Squire (1864-1943) (Box-folder 4:41, Box-folder 4:42, Box-folder 4:43, Box-folder 4:44, Box-folder 4:45, Box-folder 4:46, Box-folder 4:47, Box-folder 4:48, Box-folder 4:49)
  - Nichols, Minerva Parker (1863-1949) (Box-folder 4:50)
  - Northman, Edith Mortensen (1893-1966) (Box-folder 4:51)
  - Page, Mary Louisa (1849-1921) (Box-folder 4:52)
  - Page, Margaret Witter (1891-1974) (Box-folder 4:53)
  - Parug (Martha) Jane Moorehead (1922-1966) (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Pierce, Irene Margaret McFaul (1897-1979) (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Prussin, Labelle (1929-?) (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Reiss, Hilde Marion (Friedman) (1909-2002) (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Box 4 Index, n.d. (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Rice, Lilian Jeanette (1889-1938) (Box-folder 5:6, Box-folder 5:7)
  - Riggs, Lutah Maria (1896-1984) (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Rockfellow, Annie Graham (1866-1964) (Box-folder 5:9)
  - Rowe, Ruth Abbot (1893-1976) (Box-folder 5:10)
  - Shore, Cora H. (1871-1940) (Box-folder 5:11)
  - Sanford, Florence T. Hincks (1886-1967) (Box-folder 5:12)
  - Simonson, Penelope Murdock (1889-1980) (Box-folder 5:13)
  - Slocum, Flora Hazel (1890-19??) (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Smith, Frances Norris Rand (1878-n.d.) (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Spencer, Jeanette R, Dyer (1892-1986) (Box-folder 5:16)
  - Stan, "Sally" (Sara Ellen) Waldner Bould (1917-2008) (Box-folder 5:17)
  - Steele, Francis (1913-1981) (Box-folder 5:18)
  - Steinmesch, Henrietta May (1893-1979) (Box-folder 5:19)
  - Sumner, Charles K. (1874-1948) (Box-folder 5:20)
  - Sutherland, Helen Earle (1897-1981) (Box-folder 5:21)
  - Symons, Avesia Francia Atkins (1884-1977) (Box-folder 5:22)
  - Thompson, Elizabeth Kendall (1910-1998) (Box-folder 5:23)
  - Van Leer, Ella Wall (1892-1986) (Box-folder 5:24)
  - Warwick, Lois Dilworth (1909-1989) (Box-folder 5:25)
  - Waterman, Hazel Wood (1866-1948) (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Webster, Honor Easton (1906-1972) (Box-folder 5:27)
  - Wells, Mary Frances Knee (1897-1977) (Box-folder 5:28)
  - Williams, Emily Eolian (1869-1942) (Box-folder 5:35, Box-folder 5:36, Box-folder 5:37, Box-folder 5:38, Box-folder 5:39, Box-folder 5:40, Box-folder 5:41, Box-folder 5:42, Box-folder 5:43, Box-folder 5:44)
  - Wilson, Zelma Gussin (1918-1996) (Box-folder 5:45)
  - Witkin, Elizabeth "Betty" Ord Hilier, also Tarris, Elizabeth (1913-1972) (Box-folder 5:46, Box-folder 5:47)
  - Woods, Beulah Beatrice (1896-1986) (Box-folder 5:48)
  - Woodward, Barbara Skiles (1927-) (Box-folder 5:49)
  - Wren, Helen Rolph (1892-1986) (Box-folder 5:50)
  - Wurster, Catherine Bauer (1906-1964) (Box-folder 5:51)
  - Younger, Margaret Chase (1902-1994) (Box-folder 5:52)
  - Various Women Architects, n.d. (Box-folder 5:53)
  - Berkeley Architectural Heritage Association: The Residential Work of Five Women Architects, n.d. (Box-folder 5:54)
  - Women Architects in Los Angeles: Exhibitions and articles, odds and ends, n.d. (Box-folder 5:55)
  - Women Architects in Los Angeles: Edla Muir, n.d. (Box-folder 5:56)
  - Women Architects in San Diego: Women in Architecture 1988 House Tour, brochure (Box-folder 5:57)
  - Women Architects in Santa Barbara: The Moody Sisters, n.d. (Box-folder 5:58)
  - Women Architects in New York: Alliance of Women in Architecture, Built by Women - A Guide To Architecture in New York, 1981 (Box-folder 5:59)
  - Women Architects in the USA, n.d. (Box-folder 5:60)
  - Women Architects elsewhere in the United States and Europe - odds and ends, n.d. (Box-folder 5:61)
  - Women Architects in Switzerland: Evelyne Lang Jacob, Les Premieres Femmes Architectes de Suisse, n.d. (Box-folder 5:62)
  - Women Architects in Austria, 1984 (Box-folder 5:63)
  - UC Women Students in Engineering, n.d. (Box-folder 6:1)
  - UC Women Students in Engineering: Elizabeth Bragg Cummings, n.d. (Box-folder 6:2)
  - UC Women Students in Engineering: Millia Medbury Reed, n.d. (Box-folder 6:3)
  - UC Women Students in Engineering: Caroline Willard Baldwin Morrsion, n.d. (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Women Landscape Architects: miscellaneous files, n.d. (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Register of the University of California, 1870-1895 (Box-folder 6:6)
  - University of California, Statistics of male/female students, 1870-1920 (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Rosa Letitia Scrivner Robinson, n.d. (Box-folder 6:8)
  - Co-education at the University of California, n.d. (Box-folder 6:9)
  - Women Students at the University of California,n.d. (Box-folder 6:10)
  - Support of Women Students at the University of California, n.d. (Box-folder 6:11)
  - Initial Research of Women in Architecture at UCB, n.d. (Box-folder 6:12)
  - List of Women Students in Architecture at UCB, n.d. (Box-folder 6:13)
  - Architectural Education in General, n.d. (Box-folder 6:14)
  - History of the Architecture Department at UC Berkeley, 1993 (Box-folder 6:15)
  - Women Faculty in Architecture, Landscape Architecture and City Planning at UC Berkeley, n.d. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Women Students at the California School of Mechanical Arts or Lick Wilmerding High School, n.d. (Box-folder 6:17)
  - Women Students at Stanford University, n.d. (Box-folder 6:18)
  - Women Students at the University of Southern California, n.d. (Box-folder 6:19)
  - Women Students at Cal Poly San Luis Obispo, n.d. (Box-folder 6:20)
  - Women Students at the New York School of Applied Design, n.d. (Box-folder 6:21)
  - Women Students at the Cooper Union, New York, n.d. (Box-folder 6:22)
  - Alpha Alpha Gamma and AWA History and Keystone Newsletters, membership lists, File 1, n.d. (Box-folder 6:23)
  - Alpha Alpha Gamma and AWA with biographies of Southern California Members, File 2, n.d. (Box-folder 6:24)
  - AWA Association for Women in Architecture, n.d. (Box-folder 6:25)
  - Women in Architecture Conferences in 1972 (Box-folder 6:26)
  - Women's clubs and YWCAs, n.d. (Box-folder 6:27)
  - California Licensing or Architecture Board, n.d. (Box-folder 6:28)
  - Women Architects as War Workers, n.d. (Box-folder 6:29)
  - Women Architects in City Directories under Classified and Census, n.d. (Box-folder 6:30)
  - Women Members and Fellows of the American Institute of Architects (AIA), n.d. (Box-folder 6:31)
  - Folder List of Files of Early Women Architects and A Few Male Architects Who Support Them, n.d. (Box-folder 6:32)
- Contemporary Women Architects
  - Box 6 Index, n.d. (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Adam, Katrin,n.d. (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Almeida, Marilia Sant'Anna de, n.d. (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Anderson, Katherine, n.d. (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Armsden, Catherine, 1991 (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Aulenti, Gae, 2003 (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Autumn, Violenta, n.d. (Box-folder 7:7)
  - Bertrand, Wendy Scott, 1989 (Box-folder 7:8)
  - Bloomfield, Anne Buenger (1932-1999) (Box-folder 7:9)
  - Bogatay, Lucia, 1991 (Box-folder 7:10)
  - Brocchini, Myra of Brocchini Architects, 1991 (Box-folder 7:11)
  - Brown, Barbara, 1991 (Box-folder 7:12)
  - Budd, Katherine Clotheal (1860-1961), 1860-1961 (Box-folder 7:13)
  - Carey, Alice, Carey & Company, Inc. San Francisco, n.d. (Box-folder 7:14)
  - Casida, Kati, 1991 (Box-folder 7:15)
  - Cervantes, Anne Marie, n.d. (Box-folder 7:16)
  - Chiang, Jeanne M., 1991 (Box-folder 7:17)
  - Clendenin, Heather, 1991 (Box-folder 7:18)
  - Cochran, Andrea, n.d. (Box-folder 7:19)
  - Coffin, Christie Johnson, 1991 (Box-folder 7:20)
  - Coliver, Susie, 1991 (Box-folder 7:21)
  - Crane, Cheryl, 1991 (Box-folder 7:22)
  - Crane, Janet, n.d. (Box-folder 7:23)
  - Cruise, Kathleen, n.d. (Box-folder 7:24)
  - Crutcher, Judith Wolf, n.d. (Box-folder 7:25)
  - Danadjieva, Angela of Danadjieva & Koenig, n.d. (Box-folder 7:26)
  - Day, Kim, n.d. (Box-folder 7:27)
  - Delaney, Topher, n.d. (Box-folder 7:28)
  - Dev, Gita, 1991 (Box-folder 7:29)
  - Ecuadorian Women Architects (Box-folder 7:30)
  - Duncombe, Jane, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 7:31)
  - Favro, Diane, n.d. (Box-folder 7:32)
  - Felch, Stephanie, 1991 (Box-folder 7:33)
  - Fisher, Bonnie, 1991 (Box-folder 7:34)
  - Fraser, Carol, n.d. (Box-folder 7:35)
  - Fougeron, Anne, FAIA, n.d. (Box-folder 7:36)
  - Gottlieb, Lois Davidson, n.d. (Box-folder 7:37)
  - Gleason, Kate, n.d. (Box-folder 7:38)
  - Griffin, M. Helen, n.d. (Box-folder 7:39)
  - Griffin, Marion Mahoney, 2008 (Box-folder 7:40)
  - Hadid, Zaha, n.d. (Box-folder 7:41)
  - Hallberg, Joan, n.d. (Box-folder 7:42)
  - Hansen, Fani Danadjieva, 1991 (Box-folder 7:43)
  - Harkness, Sarah Pillsbury, n.d. (Box-folder 7:44)
  - Harling, Elisabeth-Charlotte (1922-2011) (Box-folder 7:45)
  - Hartman, Lara of Fernau & Hartman Architects, 1991 (Box-folder 7:46)
  - Hayden, Dolores with Gail Dunbow and Carolyn Flynn, Los Angeles, n.d. (Box-folder 7:47)
  - Ho, Mui, 1991 (Box-folder 7:48)
  - Hood, Bobbie Sue FAIA, formerly of Hood Miller Associates, 1991 (Box-folder 7:49)
  - House, Cathi of House & House Architects, San Francisco, n.d. (Box-folder 7:50)
  - Howard, Lucia, partner of Ace Architects, Oakland, California, 1991 (Box-folder 7:51)
  - Jang, Darlene of Barcelon & Jang Architecture/Urban Planning, n.d. (Box-folder 7:52)
  - Jansone-deFisher, Vera E. (1916-2004) (Box-folder 7:53)
  - Jewell, Linda, landscape architect and Professor of Landscape Architecture and Urban Design, 1986 (Box-folder 7:54)
  - Johnson, Kathleen, 1991 (Box-folder 7:55)
  - Kaufman, Michelle of MK Design, n.d. (Box-folder 7:56)
  - Kwan, Sylvia, architect, n.d. (Box-folder 7:57)
  - Laleyan, Marie of Laleyan Associates, Architects, 1976, 1991 (Box-folder 7:58)
  - Levi, Anna Bofill, n.d. (Box-folder 7:59)
  - Levin, Brenda, 2001 (Box-folder 7:60)
  - Levine, Sally of Cary (Chicks in Architecture Refuse to Yield Chicago), 1996 (Box-folder 7:61)
  - Levy, Toby S. of Levy Design Partners, Inc., 1991 (Box-folder 7:62)
  - Lin, Maya, n.d. (Box-folder 7:63)
  - Ling, Guo Xiao, n.d. (Box-folder 7:64)
  - Litman-Cleper, Aviva, n.d. (Box-folder 7:65)
  - Lucas, Andrea, also Andrea Lucas Kendrick of Sites Pacific Environmental Landscape Architecture, n.d. (Box-folder 7:66)
  - Macris, Marjorie, n.d. (Box-folder 7:67)
  - Mahoney, Colleen, of Mahoney Architects, Tiburon, California, n.d. (Box-folder 7:68)
  - Margrill, Anita, 1988 (Box-folder 7:69)
  - Martin-Vegue, Phyllis of Simon Martin-Vegue Winkelstein Morris of San Francisco, 1991 (Box-folder 7:70)
  - Maytum, Marsha of Tanner Leddy Maytum Stacy Architects, 1991 (Box-folder 7:71)
  - McAfee-Duncan, Charyl and McAfee-Mitchell, Sheryl, architects, n.d. (Box-folder 7:72)
  - McCoy, Esther, n.d. (Box-folder 7:73)
  - Mendelsohn, Louise and Esther Mendelsohn Joseph, 1964 (Box-folder 7:74)
  - Meterparel, Corazon of Meterparel and Associates, Daly City, California, 1991 (Box-folder 7:75)
  - Miller, Sandra of Friedman, Sagar, McCarthy & Miller, and of Howard Friedman and Claude Stoller, 1991 (Box-folder 7:76)
  - Motzkin, Patricia, 1991 (Box-folder 7:77)
  - Muller, Rosemary of Muller & Associates, architect and engineer, 1991 (Box-folder 7:78)
  - Pavlovic, Gordana of Design Studio Gordana LLC, Palo Alto, California, n.d. (Box-folder 7:79)
  - Raupach, Kristina, n.d. (Box-folder 7:80)
  - Reif, Carol of Peters, Clayberg & Caulfield, San Francisco, n.d. (Box-folder 7:81)
  - Richardson, Heidi (Hildegard) A. of Richardson Butler Architects San Francisco, 1991 (Box-folder 7:82)
  - Ripley, Cynthia of Ripley Associates, 1991 (Box-folder 7:83)
  - Rowe, Judy L. Vice President of MWM, Oakland, California, 1991 (Box-folder 7:84)
  - Rupp, Sigrid Lorenzen (1943-2004) (Box-folder 7:85)
  - San Diego Women in Architecture (WIA), n.d. (Box-folder 7:86)
  - Santos, Adele, n.d. (Box-folder 7:87)
  - Scheinholtz, Nancy of Scheinholtz Associates, 1991 (Box-folder 7:88)
  - Schmidt-Thomsen, Helga, architect of Berlin, Germany, 1987 (Box-folder 7:89)
  - Sevilla, Teresa, architect of Berkeley, California, 1991 (Box-folder 7:90)
  - Simon, Cathy J. FAIA, of Simon Martin-Vegue Winkelstein Morris of San Francisco, California, 1991 (Box-folder 7:91)
  - Sklarek, Norma FAIA, n.d. (Box-folder 7:92)
  - Som, Helen Woo and Harry Som of Som & Associates, San Francisco, 1991 (Box-folder 7:93)
  - Stavi, Jacqueline of J. Stavi Architects, San Francisco, CA, 1991 (Box-folder 7:94)
  - Solomon, Barbara Stauffer, Landscape Artist of San Francisco, n.d. (Box-folder 7:95)
  - Stothers, Marda Quon, architect and business manager of Berkeley, 2003 (Box-folder 7:96)
  - Sullivan, Ann Younggreen, n.d. (Box-folder 7:97)
  - Tanfield, Jane architect with Backen Arrigoni & Ross, 1991 (Box-folder 7:98)
  - Truchlikova, Danica of SOM, 1991 (Box-folder 7:99)
  - Various Women Architects Worldwide, n.d. (Box-folder 7:100)
  - Vilett, Helen of Vilett Architects, Berkeley, California, 1991 (Box-folder 7:101)
  - Watkin, Rebecca "Becky" Wood (Esherick), 1913-2010 (Box-folder 7:102)
  - Willis, Beverly, FAIA, architect of San Francisco, 1991 (Box-folder 7:103, Box-folder 7:104)
  - Woo, Kai Yee, of Kai-Yee Woo & Associates of San Francisco, interior design, 1991 (Box-folder 7:105)
  - Yandell, Lynn of Crosby, Helmich, Yandell & Drake, architects, 1991 (Box-folder 7:106)
- Articles of Women Architects and Other Topics, n.d.
  - Feminine Qualities in Architecture - Fact of Fiction, 1980 (Box-folder 8:1)
  - In Memoriam of Louise Mendelsohn, 1980 (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Motivation von Amerikanischen Buergern zur Partizipation, 1981 (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Opening Night of Exhibition about the History of Women Architects and Designers of 20th Century in Europe, 1987 (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Women and Architecture, a presentation, 1987 (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Lecture by Sara Boutelle and Walking Tour to Julia Morgan Buildings in Chinatown, 1988 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Protecting Housing - What's Happening in San Francisco, 1988 (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Workshop on History of Women Architects, 1989 (Box-folder 8:8)